<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Ertugrul Ghazi</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="life_intro">The most common introduction of Ertugrul is the father of Osman I, the founder of the Great Ottoman Empire. He was the son of Suleyman Shah, leader of the Kayı tribe of Oghuz Turks(we will discuss it in detail), who fled from eastern Iran to Anatolia to escape the Mongol conquests. Mongol were at their peak under the command of Khan of Khans, Genghis Khan. After the death of his Sulyman Shah, Ertuğrul and his followers entered the service of the Alā ad-Dīn Kayqubād bin Kaykāvūs, Seljuq Sultan of Rûm, Sultan rewarded him later with the town of Söğüt on the frontier with the Byzantine Empire. This set off the chain of events that would ultimately lead to the founding of the Ottoman Empire. Ertuğrul is referred to as a Ghazi, a heroic champion fighter for the cause of Islam.</string>
    <string name="Oghuz_turks">Oghuz warriors served in almost all Islamic armies of the Middle East from the 1000s onwards, in Byzantium from the 800s, and even in Spain and Morocco. The founders of the Ottoman Empire were descendants of the Oguz Yabgu State. Today the residents of Turkey, Turkmenistan, Azerbaijan, Khorezm, Turkmens of Afghanistan, Gagauzia and Iranian Azerbaijan are descendants of Oghuz Turks and their language belongs to the Oghuz (a.k.a. southwestern Turkic) group of the Turkic languages family. According to Khazar sources, Oghuzes are the seventh son of Togarmah related to Gog and Magog.</string>
    <string name="life_fam_det">Father‎: ‎Suleyman-Shah\nMother‎: ‎Hayme-Hatun \nReligion‎: ‎Sunni-Islam \nBorn: Ahlat-Turkey\n Spouse: Halime-Hatun \nChildren: Osman-I, Gündüz-Alp, Saru Batu Savcı Bey</string>
    <string name="Kayi_tribe">The Kayı tribe was an Oghuz Turkic people tribe. The word kayı means \"the one who has might and power by relationship\". According to Ottoman tradition, Osman I, founder of Ottoman Empire, was descended from the Kayı tribe. In 1227, Ertugrul inherited the command of the Kayı tribe of the Oghuz Turks as a result of his assistance to the Seljuks against the Byzantines.</string>
    <string name="life_characters"><![CDATA[ \Osman I  \n \n Osman is known as the father of the Ottoman Empire as from his Beylik (principality) the expansion of the Ottoman territory began. In the history books you will often see Ottoman rule referred to as the Osmanli dynasty. Osman came very late to his parents. He was born late in Ertugrul and Halime’s life. When Osman was born, (1258), Ertugrul was around 67 years old, and as Halime was older too, when normally women cannot have children anymore, he was considered as a Miracle sent by God. Historians consider a black hole in Ottoman history during life of Osman as what is written about him was uncovered 100 years after he died.\n \n Sultan Alā ad–Dīn Kayqubād bin Kaykāvūs \n \n  Seljuq Sultan of Rûm who reigned from 1220 to 1237. He expanded the borders of the sultanate at the expense of his neighbors, particularly the Mengujek Beylik and the Ayyubids, and established a Seljuq presence on the Mediterranean with his acquisition of the port of Kalon Oros, later renamed Alaiyya in his honor. He also brought the southern Crimea under Turkish control for a brief period as a result of a raid against the Black Sea port of Sudak. The sultan, sometimes styled "Kayqubad the Great", is remembered today for his rich architectural legacy and the brilliant court culture that flourished under his reign. \n \n  Gundogdu & Sungurtekin  \n\n They did not support Ertugrul path and as we know, and over time faded in history. They lived a quiet and unremarkable life, not much is known or written about them. There are only verbal accounts, which were told by people through generations. According to that, they suffered big losses during a great Mongol invasion, and what was left of them, they lived subserviently under the Mongol’s rule! \n \n Dundar Bey \n \n  He was a brave and renown warrior, a goodhearted and loving man, devoted to his brother, his tribe, and  his family. But history documents him as a weak personality and he made a lot of mistakes and throughout his long life. He died aged 92 or 93, by hands of Sultan Osman. He rebelled against one of the decision of Osman and that was the last straw for Osman. \n  \n Turgut Alp \n  \n He was one of the greatest and most renown warriors in Turkish history, a blood-brother to Ertugrul and his best follower and supporter, a very smart and capable man.He lived an unusually long life, even for our time. He outlived Erugrul Bey by 35 years, and he was killed in a battle, with his legendary battle-axe in his hand aged 125 years old! After Ertugrul passed away, Turgut become the main support to Osman, and when Osman established his Sultanate he rewarded Turgut with the highest position, as a Governor of the new State. \n \n Bamsi Beyrek \n \n He was a legendary hero; his life has been described in the book of medieval Ottomans chronologies of that time, titled \"The book of Dede Korkut\" . He was a fierce warrior, goodhearted and very funny man. His love life was legendary, since his heart was divided between two loves. He spent 16 years in a dungeon in Byzantine, and the Princess, who lived in that Fortress fell in love with him and helped him escape. It is not known when he died or how long he lived! only that he lived fairly long for that time, and that he was ambushed by trickery and killed, leaving behind a wife and children. \n \n ibn arabi \n \n  Ibn Arabi  As many of us know Ibn Arabi is a famous chronologist, mystic, philosopher, poet, sage, he is one of the world’s great spiritual teachers. Ibn Arabi was born in Murcia, Andalusia, in Spain in 1165 and his writings had an immense impact throughout the Islamic world and Christian world. The universal ideas underlying his thought are of immediate relevance today. He was great inspiration and support to Ertugrul Bey. He died 1240 aged 75.  After his death, Ertugrul Bey continued to draw support from Ibn Arabi, through his numerous writings, books, diaries, teachings and his other spiritual works, and through his followers. \n \n Halime Sultan \n \n She was a Seljuk Princess, very dedicated to her husband and his greatest supporter. She gave up her title and her Palace life due to her love and dedication to Ertugrul Bey. Through her marriage to Ertugrul Bey, Seljuk Turks and Oguz Turks, two greatest Turkish branches were irrevocably united by blood ties. \n \n Hayme Mother \n \n She lived a long life and she came with them all the way to Sogut.  She was a smart, caring and brave woman, who acted as the Bey of her tribe, after Suleyman Shah had died. She was widely much respected and she was called \"the Mother of the people\".  \n \n It is not clear whether she gave birth to Gundogdu, she certainly brought him up. According to one line of sources, Gundogdu was her own son. But, since Suleyman Shah had lost his first wife, before marring Hayme, there are some who believe that Gundogdu was born by that young woman.  \n \n  Suleyman Shah  \n \n  He was a greatly respected figure of that time, he had 4 sons with Hayme Mother. He died by drowning in River Euphrates, and the spot near Aleppo, where he was buried in a sacred place for Turks which is now in modern day Syria.  \n \n That territory still belongs to Turkey, it is guarded by Turkey’s military guards and you need a passport to get in there, to see the mausoleum of Suleyman Shah.   \n \n Although due to the emergence of ISIS and the recent ruin of shrines and tombs from extremists, the remains were temporarily removed last year due to the situation around Aleppo, and brought to Turkey to preserve. \n \n Saddetin Kopek  \n \n According to Ottoman sources Saddetin Kopek is considered an ambitious and evil  man, his only good quality was his devotion to his State. He eventually managed to kill Sultan Aleaddin, his second wife, the Ayyubid Princess and their two sons by poisoning in 1238. He then proclaimed Sultan Aleaddin’s third and oldest son (from his first marriage), as a new Sultan through whom Kopek gained a total power. However, only one year later, he was hanged from the Palace wall. \n \n Noyan \n \n Noyan was a title of authority in the Mongol Empire and later periods. Baycu Noyan was a Mongol commander in Persia, or present-day Iran (1230–1260). He was appointed by Ögedei Khan to succeed Chormagan, and expand Mongol power further in that area. Baiju took over command in 1241 or 1242, and immediately moved against the Seljuk Sultanate of Rûm, shattering its power at the Battle of Köse Dağ in 1243. After this battle, the Sultanate became a vassal state of the Mongol empire and was forced to release David VII Ulu. He  led Mongol tumens to raid Syria in 1246. Despite his small successes there, his next two attempts to invade the Abbasid Caliphate in Iraq met less success in 1238-1246.  According to Rashid al-Din, Baiju was executed by Hülegü Khan due to failing to stop Golden Horde corps fleeing from Persia to Russia and Mamluks. Sad End! \n \n artuk bey \n \n Artuk Bey  Known as Ertugrul Bey’s right hand man in the TV series, but there is so much more to his story! Artuk Bey (also known as “Son of Eksük” or Ibn Eksuk) was a Turkish General of the Great Seljuk Empire in the 11th century. He was the Seljuk governor of Jerusalem between 1085–1091. Artuk Bey lived in Qüddus up to his death in 1091.  Artuk Bey was one of the commanders of the Great Seljuk Empire army during the Battle of Manzikert in 1071. After the battle, he took part in the conquest of Anatolia on behalf of the Seljuk Empire. \n He captured the Yeşilırmak valley in 1074. He also served the sultan by quashing a rebellion in 1077.  His next mission was a campaign to capture Amid (modern Diyarbakır) from the Marwanids. In this campaign he quarrelled with the Commander in Chief Fahrüddevlet who tended to make peace with Marwanids. In a surprise attack he defeated reinforcements to Marwanids. However, when the Sultan Malik Shah I heard about the event he suspected Artuk Bey of dissension.  Artuk Bey left the battle field and attended to Tutush I who was Malik Shah’s discordant younger brother in Syria in 1084. \n  \n In 1086 he was instrumental in defeating Süleyman, the sultan of Seljuks of Turkey in a battle between Süleyman and Tutush.  The Beylik of Artukids was named after him, founded 11 years after his death by his sons. His valiant sons are El Gazi ibn Artuk who battled Baldwin II of Edessa at the Battle of Hab, Syria (1119) but lost and Soqman ibn Artuk, the ally of the hot tempered Tugtekin Bey, The Governor of Damascus against the Crusaders in 1104 at the Battle of Harran near Raqqa.  \n  \n On this battle the Seljuk Army finally captured Crusader Knights Baldwin Il of Edessa who called himself, King of Tripoli and Jerusalem and Joscelin of Courtenay who called himself Prince of Galilee. Although, they managed to escape later. Soqman ibn Artuk become famous and a true honour to the late Artuk Bey. \n \n Emir Al-Aziz  of Aleppo  \n \n  Emir Al-Aziz  of Aleppo  Al Aziz Muhammad ibn Gazi (1213 – 1236) was the Ayyubi Emir of Aleppo and the son of az-Zahir Gazi (r) and grandson of the great Salahuddin Al Ayubi (r), the liberator of Jerusalem from the Crusaders and Templars. His mother was Dayfa Khatun(r), the daughter of Salahuddin’s brother al-Adil(r). Al-Aziz was aged just three when his father az-Zahir Gazi died in 1216 at the age of forty-five. \n \n He immediately inherited his father’s position as ruler of Aleppo. A regency council was formed, which appointed Shihab ad-Din Tughril(r) as his guardian. \n \n  Tughril was a Mamluk of az-Zahir Gazi and the effective ruler of Aleppo for the next fifteen years.  Al-Aziz did not take actual control of power until the age of seventeen, at which point he retained Tughril as his treasurer. In general, he avoided becoming drawn into the complex disputes between different members of the Ayyubi dynasty, and concentrated instead on strengthening the defenses and infrastructure of Aleppo. Among the construction works begun by az-Zahir Gazi and completed by al-Aziz Muhammad were the re-fortification of the citadel, and, within it, the building of the palace, the mosque, the arsenal and the water cisterns.  \n \n Al-Aziz is known to have married Fatima Khatun, daughter of al-Kamil, who apparently shared his passion for building and commissioned the construction of two madrasas in Aleppo. Al-Aziz died on 26 November 1236 at the age of just twenty-three. His eldest son, an-Nasir Yusuf, was only seven years old, so al-Aziz’s mother Dayfa Khatun assumed the regency. Surprisingly, Al-Aziz’s daughter, Ghaziya Khatun, married the Seljuk Sultan of Rum, Kaykhusraw II (Giyaseddin Ibn Kayqubad) \n Credits: islamichistoryproject.com]]></string>

    <string name="life_death">Died: 1281, Söğüt, Turkey \n Buried: Tomb of Ertuğrul Gazi, Söğüt, Turkey \n \n A tomb and mosque dedicated to Ertuğrul is said to have been built by Osman I at Söğüt, but due to several rebuildings nothing certain can be said about the origin of these structures. The current mausoleum was built by sultan Abdul Hamid II in the late nineteenth century. The town of Söğüt celebrates an annual festival to the memory of the early Osmans.</string>

    <string name="war_start">Before we start talking on the wars of Osmanis, we first must understand what was going on at that time in the world!</string>

    <string name="war_suljuk_begining">This the map of Great Sulkuj Sultanate of Rum before Mongol invasion. Mongol invasions of Anatolia occurred at various times, starting with the campaign of 1241–1243 that culminated in the Battle of Köse Dağ. Real power over Anatolia was exercised by the Mongols after the Seljuks surrendered in 1243 until the fall of the Ilkhanate in 1335.\n \n Because the Seljuk Sultan rebelled several times, in 1255, the Mongols swept through central and eastern Anatolia. The Ilkhanate garrison was stationed near Ankara.  Timur\'s invasion is sometimes considered the last invasion of Anatolia by the Mongols. Remains of the Mongol cultural heritage still can be seen in Turkey, including tombs of a Mongol governor and a son of Hulagu.\n \n By the end of the 14th century, most of Anatolia was controlled by various Anatolian beyliks due to the collapse of the Seljuk dynasty in Rum. The Turkmen Beyliks were under the control of the Mongols through declining Seljuk Sultans. The Beyliks did not mint coins in the names of their own leaders while they remained under the suzerainty of the Ilkhanids.\n \n The Ottoman ruler Osman I was the first Turkish ruler who minted coins in his own name in the 1320s, for it bears the legend \"Minted by Osman son of Ertuğrul\". Since the minting of coins was a prerogative accorded in Islamic practice only to be a sovereign, it can be considered that the Ottomans became independent of the Mongol Khans.</string>
    <string name="war_suljuk_middle">Map of Suljuk Empire controlled by Mongols. The control of Anatolia was then split between the Greek states and the Seljuk Sultanate of Rum, with the Byzantine holdings gradually being reduced.\n \n The Mongol Empire conquered Persia in 1230; Chormaqan became military governor. There were then no hostilities with the Seljuk Turks. \'Ala al-Din Kayqubad I and his immediate successor Giyath al-Din Kaykhusraw II swore an oath of vassalage with the payment of at least token tribute to the Great Khan Ögedei.\n \n However, in 1238 the Mongols raided part of Greater Armenia, which was a vassal of the Sultanate of Rum. Ögedei died in 1241, and Kaykhusraw took the opportunity to repudiate his vassalage, believing he was strong enough to resist the Mongols. Chormaqan\'s successor Baiju Noyan summoned him to renew his submission: go to Mongolia in person, give hostages, and accept a Mongol darughachi(Governorship).\n \n When the Sultan refused, Baiju Noyan declared war.</string>
    <string name="war_suljuk_middle1">The Final Battle \n \nThe Seljuks invaded the Kingdom of Georgia, part of the Mongol Empire. Baiju Noyan\'s army attacked Karin in relation to Kaykhusraw\'s disobedience in 1241. Before attacking, Baiju Noyan demanded submission. The inhabitants of the city insulted the Mongol envoy sent by him. Since the city decided to resist and defied Mongol diplomacy, the Mongols besieged it.\n \n In two months, the Mongols took Karin and punished its residents. Aware of the Seljuk power in Anatolia, Noyan returned to the Mugan plain without advancing further. Baiju advanced to Erzurum with a contingent of Georgian and Armenian warriors under Awag and Shansheh in 1243. They besieged the city of Erzurum when its governor Yakut refused to surrender it. With the power of twelve catapults, Baiju stormed Erzurum.\n \n When the reports of the attack on Erzurum reported to him, Kaykhusraw summoned his armed forces at Konya. He accepted the challenge by sending a war message, defying Baiju that his army took only one of his many cities. The Seljuk Sultan made an alliance with all nations surrounding him. The King of Lesser Armenia (Armenian Kingdom of Cilicia) promised him to send a contingent; however, it is not certain they really engaged in his struggle with the Mongols.\n \n Kaykhusraw received the military support from the Empire of Trebizond and the Ayyubid Sultan at Aleppo, and the Frankish mercenaries participated in the campaign. Because of little reliable information, it is difficult to measure the opposing troops.\n \n Kaykhusraw advanced from Konya some 200 miles up to Köse Dağ. The Mongolian army entered the area in June 1243 and awaited the march of the Seljuks and their allies. The early stage of the battle was indecisive. The Sultan\'s forces suffered the greater casualties and he decided to withdraw at night.\n \n Pursuing him, Baiju Noyan received the submission of Erzinjan, Divrigi and Sivas en route.  The Mongols set up their camp near Sivas. When the Mongols penetrated into Kayseri, it chose to resist them. After a short resistance, it fell to the invaders. Hearing of the disaster at Köse Dağ, Hethum I of Armenian Kingdom of Cilicia quickly made his peace with the Mongols in 1243 and sent his brother Sembat to the Mongol court of Karakorum in 1247 to negotiate an alliance with the Mongolian Emperor Güyük. Kaykhusraw sent a delegation headed by his vizier to Baiju, realizing the further resistance would only produce a great disaster.\n \n Baiju Noyan offered terms based on resubmission and the Sultan was undertaken to pay a tribute tax every year in gold, silk, camel and sheep of uncertain quantities. However, the Turkish realm that had been taken by the military force remained occupied by the Mongols. Almost half of the Sultanate of Rum became an occupied country. The Empire of Trebizond became subject to the Mongolian Qaghan, fearing of the potential punitive expedition because they involved in the battle of Köse Dağ.</string>
    <string name="war_suljuk_end">\n The disintegration of the Seljuk Turks led to the rise of the Ottoman Turks. Their first important leader was Osman I Bey, who attracted Ghazi warriors and carved out a domain in north-western Asia Minor. Attempts by the Byzantine Emperors to drive back the Ottomans were unsuccessful, and ceased in 1329 with the Battle of Pelekanon. Following a number of civil disputes in the Byzantine Empire, the Ottomans subjugated the Byzantines as vassals in the late 14th century and attempts to relieve this vassal status culminated in the Fall of Constantinople in 1453.</string>
    <string name="war_suljuk_end1">In 1301, after soundly defeating a Byzantine force near Nikea, Osman began settling his forces closer to Byzantine-controlled areas. Large numbers of Ghazi warriors, Islamic scholars, and dervishes began settling in Osman-controlled areas, and migrants composed the bulk of his army.\n \n The influx of Ghazi warriors and adventurers of differing backgrounds into these lands spurred subsequent Ottoman rulers to title themselves \"Sultan of Ghazis\".  \n Osman\'s last campaign, before dying of old age, was against the Byzantines in the city of Bursa.\n \n Although Osman did not physically participate in the battle, the victory at Bursa proved to be extremely vital for the Ottomans as the city served as a staging ground against the Byzantines in Constantinople, and as a newly adorned capital for Osman\'s son, Orhan.\n \n The Fall of Constantinople was the capture of the capital of the Byzantine Empire by an invading Ottoman army on 29 May 1453. The attackers were commanded by the 21-year-old Sultan Mehmed II, who defeated an army commanded by Emperor Constantine XI Palaiologos and took control of the imperial capital, ending a 53-day siege that began on 6 April 1453.\n \n After conquering the city, Sultan Mehmed transferred the capital of his Empire from Edirne to Constantinople and established his court there.  The capture of the city (and two other Byzantine splinter territories soon thereafter) marked the end of the Byzantine Empire, a continuation of the Roman Empire, an imperial state dating to 27 BC, which had lasted for nearly 1,500 years.\n \n The conquest of Constantinople also dealt a massive blow to Christendom, as the Muslim Ottoman armies thereafter were left unchecked to advance into Europe without an adversary to their rear.</string>
    <string name="empire_intro0">Ertugrul Ghazi\'s vision for an empire was a big reason that Osman-I was able to establish an Empire as the basis were already founded by Ertugrul. The Great Suljuk Empire was falling and most of the Bays were not considering Suljuk Sultan as their Sultan. In this time, Osman, son of Ertugrul mented coins in his name and bacome first Sultan to oppose Mongol power in era.</string>
    <string name="empire_intro">Suljuk Sultan, Ala Ad Din in recognition of the services of Ertugrul, granted him land in Sogut, modern day Turkey. Ertugrul then established a town there. After the last prince of the family of Ala-ad-Din, to which Osman\'s family had been indebted for its foundation in Asia Minor, died, there was no other among the various emirs of that country who could compete with Osman for the headship of the whole Turkish population and dominion over the whole peninsula, save the Emir of Karamanogullari.\n \n  A long and fierce struggle between the descendants of Osman and the Karamanogullari princes for the ascendancy commenced in Osman’s lifetime and was protracted during the reigns of many of his successors.\n \n Osman himself had gained some advantages over his Karamanli rival, but the rich yet vulnerable possessions of the Byzantine Emperor in the northeast of Asia Minor were more tempting marks for his ambition than the Karamanoglu plains, and it was over Greek cities and armies that the triumphs of the last 26 years of Osman’s life were achieved.\n \n Turkic peoples called themselves Osmanli until the dissolution of the Ottoman Empire in WWI. We are willing to make another application on factors of Rise and Fall of Ottoman Empire. Please give your suggestions in reviews. Thanks</string>
    <string name="p_vision">Osman was 24 at the time of his accession, and had already proven his skills as both a leader and a warrior. His early fortunes and exploits are favorite subjects with Near Eastern writers, especially love stories of his wooing and winning the fair Mal Hatun. Ottoman writers attached great importance to these legends, characteristic of dynastic mythology in medieval and biblical chronicles.  There is a well-known story about a sleepless night Osman spent before taking the throne.\n \n One day, when he was 19 years old, his father Ertugrul went to visit a distant friend with his family, where they would remain overnight. The host of the house shows Osman his room and everyone retires for the night. Just after he prepares to go to sleep Osman notices the Qur\'an hanging on the wall.\n \n His respect for the holy book of Islam keeps him from lying down, and as he is a visitor, he cannot take the Qur\'an out of the room. He decides not to sleep until morning and sits beside the sofa. However, he is unable to stay awake and falls asleep for a short time just before dawn.\n \n As he sleeps, he dreams he sees a crescent coming out of the chest of his mentor, Sheikh Edebali, and going into his body. Afterwards an enormous plane tree emerges from his chest and covers all the sky, shading the earth, the people enjoying and benefiting from his shade.\n \n He then wakes. When he and his family get back to their village, he recounts this dream to Sheikh Edebali, who smiles after hearing the dream and tells Osman that Allah would grant him and his descendants an enormous empire and he will receive the hand of Sheikh Edebali\'s daughter Mal Hatun in marriage. Because of his loyalty to Islam and his sharpness, courage, and generosity, he was nominated to be the ruler of the Kayi Clan.\n \n Ottoman sources often dwell on the prophetic significance of Osman\'s name, which means \"bone-breaker,\" signifying the powerful energy with which he and his followers showed in the following centuries of conquest. The name is also one given to a large species of vulture, commonly called the royal vulture, which is considered the emblem of sovereignty and warlike power in the East, comparable to the eagle in the nations of the West.</string>
    <string name="expension">The empire, reunited by Muhammad I, expanded victoriously under Muhammad’s successors Murad II and Muhammad II. The victory (1444) at Varna over a crusading army led by Ladislaus III of Poland was followed in 1453 by the capture of Constantinople. Within a century the Ottomans had changed from a nomadic horde to the heirs of the most ancient surviving empire of Europe.\n \n Their success was due partly to the weakness and disunity of their adversaries, partly to their excellent and far superior military organization. Their army comprised numerous Christians—not only conscripts, who were organized as the corps of Janissaries, but also volunteers.\n \n Turkish expansion reached its peak in the 16th cent. under Selim I and Sulayman I (Sulayman the Magnificent).  The Hungarian defeat (1526) at Mohács prepared the way for the capture (1541) of Buda and the absorption of the major part of Hungary by the Ottoman Empire; Transylvania became a tributary principality, as did Walachia and Moldavia.\n \n The Asian borders of the empire were pushed deep into Persia and Arabia. Selim I defeated the Mamluks of Egypt and Syria, took Cairo in 1517, and assumed the succession to the caliphate. Algiers was taken in 1518, and Mediterranean commerce was threatened by corsairs, such as Barbarossa, who sailed under Turkish auspices. Most of the Venetian and other Latin possessions in Greece also fell to the sultans.\n \n During the reign of Sulayman I began (1535) the traditional friendship between France and Turkey, directed against Hapsburg Austria and Spain. Sulayman reorganized the Turkish judicial system, and his reign saw the flowering of Turkish literature, art, and architecture. In practice the prerogatives of the sultan were limited by the spirit of Muslim canonical law (sharia), and he usually shared his authority with the chief preserver (sheyhülislam) of the sharia and with the grand vizier (chief executive officer).\n \n In the progressive decay that followed Sulayman’s death, the clergy (ulema) and the Janissaries gained power and exercised a profound, corrupting influence. The first serious blow by Europe to the empire was the naval defeat of Lepanto (1571; inflicted on the fleet of Selim II by the Spanish and Venetians under John of Austria. However, Murad IV in the 17th cent. temporarily restored Turkish military prestige by his victory (1638) over Persia. Crete was conquered from Venice, and in 1683 a huge Turkish army under Grand Vizier Kara Mustafa surrounded Vienna.\n \n The relief of Vienna by John III of Poland and the subsequent campaigns of Charles V of Lorraine, Louis of Baden, and Eugene of Savoy ended in negotiations in 1699 which cost Turkey Hungary and other territories.</string>
    <string name="expension1">The Fourth Crusade (1202 to 1204) was a Latin Christian armed expedition called by Pope Innocent III. The majority of the crusading army that set out from Venice in early October 1202 originated from areas within France. \n \n Early in October 1202, a fleet of 200 ships set sail from the lagoon of Venice. The goal of this expedition, this Fourth Crusade, was to win back the holy city of Jerusalem. Conquered by Islamic armies in the 7th century. Jerusalem fell to the Muslim Saladin, the Greatest Sultan of his time, An-Nasir Salah ad-Din Yusuf ibn Ayyub known as Sultan Salah ad-Din Ayoubi in the Muslim World, who then stalemated a recovery attempt by the Third Crusade (1189 to 92). The Fourth Crusade was to follow a new strategy: strike at Egypt, the base of Muslim power. But it never reached its goal. Instead, a bizarre twist of fate turned the latest crusaders in a totally unexpected direction! \n \n They, instead of targeting Islamic cities they attacked another Chirstian city, one of the greatest cities of all times, Constantinople, capital of the Byzantine Empire.\n \n After this attack, The Byzantine Empire never recovered and was finally and forever extinguished by the Turks in 1453. \n \n Almost none of the crusaders ever made it to the Holy Land, and the unstable Latin Empire siphoned off much of the crusading energy of Europe. The legacy of the Fourth Crusade was the deep sense of betrayal the Latins had instilled in their Greek coreligionists.\n \n Turks, after this crusade became much more powerful, actually we can say that their way into Europe was paved by 4th crusade. </string>
    <string name="expension2">The Ottoman State originated as a Beylik within the Seljuk Empire in the thirteenth century. In 1299, Osman I declared independence of the Ottoman Principality. Murad I was the first Ottoman to claim the title of Sultan (king/deputy).\n \n With the capture of Constantinople in 1453, the state was on its way to becoming a mighty Empire with Mehmed II as its emperor or padishah. The empire reached its apex under Suleiman I in the sixteenth century, when it stretched from the Persian Gulf in the east, to Hungary in the northwest, and from Egypt in the south, to the Caucasus in the north.\n \n The empire was situated in the middle of east and west and interacted throughout its six-century history with both Eastern culture and Western culture. It was in 1353 that, by capturing Gallipoli, the Ottomans gained their first foothold in Europe, blockading the Strait of the Dardanelles.\n \n The Great Ottoman Empire, founded by Osman-I, son of Ertugrul lasted for over 600 years with everlasting impact on the human history.</string>
    <string name="war_suljuk_end0">The Ottomans didn\'t invade the Mongols because the Ottomans didn\'t exist yet. The Mongols first conquered the Seljuk Turks. After that the only Turks based in Anatolia was the Sultanate of Rum. By the time the Ottomans came around in 1299, the Mongols were losing their presence and by the time the Ottomans campaigned outside Anatolia (1517), the Mongols were long gone. - Quora</string>
</resources>
