<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">

    <string name="app_name">OTTOMAN EMPIRE HISTORY</string>

    <string name="life_intro">
        The most common introduction of Ertugrul is the father of Osman I, the founder of the Great
        Ottoman Empire.\n\n He was the son of Suleyman Shah, leader of the Kayı tribe of Oghuz Turks, who
        fled from eastern Iran to Anatolia to escape the Mongol conquests.  Mongol were at their peak
        under the command of Khan of Khans, Genghis Khan.\n\n After the death of his Sulyman Shah, Ertuğrul
        and his followers entered the service of the Alā ad Dīn Kayqubād bin Kaykāvūs, Seljuq Sultan of
        Rûm.  Sultan rewarded him later with the town of Söğüt on the frontier with the Byzantine
        Empire. This set off the chain of events that would ultimately lead to the founding of the
        Ottoman Empire.\n\n  Ertuğrul is referred to as a Ghazi, a heroic champion fighter for the cause
        of Islam.
        Suljuk Sultan, Ala Ad Din in recognition of the services of Ertugrul,
        granted him land in Sogut, modern day Turkey.\n\n Ertugrul then established a town there. Söğüt
        was known as Thivasio until it was conquered by Ertuğrul Gazi in 1231. In 1299, his son Osman I
        declared independence from the ruling Selçuk Turks, thus founding the Ottoman Empire and
        becoming the first Ottoman sultan.\n\n Söğüt was the Ottoman capital until 1325 when it moved to
        Bursa. There is an monument of Ertugrul Gazi there.\n\n
</string>

    <string name="life_intro_osman">
        Osman is known as the father of the Ottoman Empire as from his Beylik (principality) the
        expansion of the Ottoman territory began.\n\n In the history books you will often see Ottoman
        rule referred to as the Osmanli dynasty. Osman came very late to his parents. He was born late
        in Ertugrul and Halime’s life.\n\n When Osman was born, (1258), Ertugrul was around 67 years
        old, and as Halime was older too, when normally women cannot have children anymore, he was
        considered as a Miracle sent by God.\n\n

        There is a well known story about a sleepless night Osman spent before taking the throne.
        One day, when he was 19 years old, his father Ertugrul went to visit a distant friend with his
        family, where they would remain overnight.\n\n The host of the house shows Osman his room and
        everyone retires for the night. Just after he prepares to go to sleep Osman notices the Quran
        hanging on the wall.\n\n His respect for the holy book of Islam keeps him from lying down, and
        as he is a visitor, he cannot take the Quran out of the room. He decides not to sleep until
        morning and sits beside the sofa. However, he is unable to stay awake and falls asleep for a
        short time just before dawn.\n\n As he sleeps, he dreams he sees a crescent coming out of the
        chest of his mentor, Sheikh Edebali, and going into his body. Afterwards an enormous plane tree
        emerges from his chest and covers all the sky, shading the earth, the people enjoying and
        benefiting from his shade.\n\n
        He then wakes. When he and his family get back to their village, he recounts this dream to
        Sheikh Edebali, who smiles after hearing the dream and tells Osman that Allah would grant him
        and his descendants an enormous empire and he will receive the hand of Sheikh Edebali\ s
        daughter Mal Hatun in marriage.\n\n Because of his loyalty to Islam and his sharpness, courage, and
        generosity, he was nominated to be the ruler of the Kayi Clan.
\n\n
        Ottoman sources often dwell on the prophetic significance of Osman name, which means
        \"bone breaker,\" signifying the powerful energy with which he and his followers showed in the
        following centuries of conquest.\n\n The name is also one given to a large species of vulture,
        commonly called the royal vulture, which is considered the emblem of sovereignty and warlike
        power in the East, comparable to the eagle in the nations of the West.\n\n
        Historians consider a black hole in Ottoman history during life of Osman as what is written
        about him was uncovered 100 years after he died.\n\n

        In 1301, after soundly defeating a Byzantine force near Nikea, Osman began settling his forces
        closer to Byzantine controlled areas. Large numbers of Ghazi warriors, Islamic scholars, and
        dervishes began settling in Osman controlled areas, and migrants composed the bulk of his
        army.\n\n The influx of Ghazi warriors and adventurers of differing backgrounds into these
        lands spurred subsequent Ottoman rulers to title themselves \"Sultan of Ghazis\". \n Osman\ s
        last campaign, before dying of old age, was against the Byzantines in the city of Bursa.\n \n
        Although Osman did not physically participate in the battle, the victory at Bursa proved to be
        extremely vital for the Ottomans as the city served as a staging ground against the Byzantines
        in Constantinople, and as a newly adorned capital for Osmans son, Orhan.\n\n  The Fall of
        Constantinople was the capture of the capital of the Byzantine Empire by an invading Ottoman
        army on 29 May 1453. The attackers were commanded by the 21 year old Sultan Mehmed II, who
        defeated an army commanded by Emperor Constantine XI Palaiologos and took control of the
        imperial capital, ending a 53 day siege that began on 6 April 1453.\n\n After conquering the
        city, Sultan Mehmed transferred the capital of his Empire from Edirne to Constantinople and
        established his court there. The capture of the city (and two other Byzantine splinter
        territories soon thereafter) marked the end of the Byzantine Empire, a continuation of the Roman
        Empire, an imperial state dating to 27 BC, which had lasted for nearly 1,500 years.\n\n The
        conquest of Constantinople also dealt a massive blow to Christendom, as the Muslim Ottoman
        armies thereafter were left unchecked to advance into Europe without an adversary to their rear.\n\n
</string>

    <string name="life_intro_orhan">
        The second Sultan of Ottomans, in the early stages of his reign, Orhan focused his energies on
        conquering most of northwestern Anatolia. The majority of these areas were under Byzantine rule
        and he won his first battle at Pelekanon against the Byzantine Emperor Andronikos III
        Palaiologos.\n\n Orhan also occupied the lands of the Karasids of Balıkesir and the Ahis of
        Ankara.
        In the Byzantine civil war of 1341–1347, the regent John VI Kantakouzenos married his daughter
        Theodora to Orhan and employed Ottoman warriors against the rival forces of the empress dowager,
        allowing them to loot Thrace.\n\n In the Byzantine civil war of 1352–1357, Kantakouzenos used
        Ottoman forces against John V, granting them the use of a European fortress at Çimpe around
        1352.\n\n
        Born in Söğüt around 1281, Orhan was the first son of Osman I. Orhan grandfather, Ertuğrul Gazi,
        named his grandson after Orhan Alp. According to Ottoman tradition, when Orhan succeeded his
        father, he proposed to his brother, Alaeddin, that they should share the emerging empire.\n\n
        Orhans predecessors, Ertuğrul and Osman I, had made war at the head of the armed vassals and
        volunteers. This army rode on horseback to their prince s banner when summoned for each
        expedition, and were disbanded as soon as the campaign was over.\n\n
        He made Janissary force. He claimed that the formation of Janissary out of conquered children
        would induce other people to adopt, not only out of the children of the conquered nations, but
        out of a crowd of their friends and relations, who would come as volunteers to join the Ottoman
        ranks.\n\n
        During Orhan s reign as the Ottoman emir, the Byzantine Empire declined – partly due to the
        ambitions of Italian maritime states and to the aggression of the Turcomans and other city
        Turks, but also due to civil wars within the empire.\n\n
        Orhan was the longest living and one of the longest reigning of the future Ottoman Sultans. In
        his last years he had left most of the powers of state in the hands of his second son Murad and
        lived a secluded life in Bursa.\n\n
        Orhan died in 1362, in Bursa, at the age of eighty, after a reign of thirty six years. He is
        buried in the türbe (tomb) with his wife and children, called Gümüşlü Kumbet in Bursa.\n\n
</string>

    <string name="life_intro_murad">
        Murad I conquered Adrianople, renamed it to Edirne, and in 1363 made it the new capital of the
        Ottoman Sultanate.\n\n
        Murad fought against the powerful beylik of Karaman in Anatolia and against the Serbs,
        Albanians, Bulgarians and Hungarians in Europe.\n\n
        In 1389, Murad s army defeated the Serbian Army and its allies under the leadership of Lazar at
        the Battle of Kosovo. There are different accounts from different sources about when and how
        Murad I was assassinated.\n\n In 1389, Murad s army defeated the Serbian Army and its allies under
        the leadership of Lazar at the Battle of Kosovo. There are different accounts from different
        sources about when and how Murad I was assassinated. In 1389, Murad s army defeated the Serbian
        Army and its allies under the leadership of Lazar at the Battle of Kosovo. There are different
        accounts from different sources about when and how Murad I was assassinated.\n\n
        He established the sultanate by building up a society and government in the newly conquered city
        of Adrianople (Edirne in Turkish) and by expanding the realm in Europe, bringing most of the
        Balkans under Ottoman rule and forcing the Byzantine emperor to pay him tribute.\n\n It was Murad
        who established the former Osmanli tribe into an sultanate. He established the title of sultan
        in 1383 and the corps of the janissaries and the devşirme recruiting system. He also organised
        the government of the Divan, the system of timars and timar holders (timariots) and the military
        judge, the kazasker.\n\n He also established the two provinces of Anadolu (Anatolia) and Rumeli
        (Europe).
</string>

    <string name="life_intro_bayezid">
        He decisively defeated the Crusaders at Nicopolis (in modern Bulgaria) in 1396, and was himself
        defeated and captured by Timur at the Battle of Ankara in 1402 and died in captivity in March
        1403, triggering the Ottoman Interregnum.\n\n
        Bayezid ascended to the throne following the death of his father Murad I, who was killed by
        Serbian knight Miloš Obilić during (15 June), or immediately after (16 June), the Battle of
        Kosovo in 1389, by which Serbia became a vassal of the Ottoman Sultanate.\n\n Immediately after
        obtaining the throne, he had his younger brother strangled to avoid a plot.
        The upper Serbia resisted the Ottomans until general Pasha Yiğit Bey captured the city of Skopje
        in 1391, converting the city to an important base of operations.\n\n
        Meanwhile, the sultan began unifying Anatolia under his rule. Forcible expansion into Muslim
        territories could endanger the Ottoman relationship with the gazis, who were an important source
        of warriors for this ruling house on the European frontier.\n\n So Bayezid began the practice to
        first secure fatwas, or legal rulings from Islamic scholars.
        From 1389 to 1395 he conquered Bulgaria and northern Greece. In 1394 Bayezid crossed the River
        Danube to attack Wallachia, ruled at that time by Mircea the Elder.\n\n
        In 1394, Bayezid laid siege to Constantinople, the capital of the Byzantine Empire.
        Anadoluhisarı fortress was built between 1393 and 1394 as part of preparations for the Second
        Ottoman Siege of Constantinople, which took place in 1395.\n\n
        In 1397, Bayezid defeated the emir of Karaman in Akçay, killing him and annexing his territory.
        In 1400, the Turco Mongol warlord Timur succeeded in rousing the local Turkic beyliks who had
        been vassals of the Ottomans to join him in his attack on Bayezid, who was also considered one
        of the most powerful rulers in the Muslim world during that period.\n\n
</string>
    <string name="life_intro_mehmet">
        The fourth son of Sultan Bayezid I and Devlet Hatun, he fought with his brothers over control of
        the Ottoman realm in the Ottoman Interregnum (1402–1413).\n\n Starting from the province of Rûm he
        managed to bring first Anatolia and then the European territories (Rumelia) under his control,
        reuniting the Ottoman state by 1413, and ruling it until his death in 1421.\n\n
        On 20 July 1402, his father Bayezid was defeated in the Battle of Ankara by the Turko Mongol
        conqueror and ruler Timur. The brothers (with the exception of Mustafa, who was captured and
        taken along with Bayezid to Samarkand) were rescued from the battlefield, Mehmed being saved by
        Bayezid Pasha, who took him to his hometown of Amasya. Mehmed later made Bayezid Pasha his grand
        vizier (1413–1421).\n\n
        Battle of Ankara and other civil wars, the population of the empire had become unstable and
        traumatized. A very powerful social and religious movement arose in the empire and became
        disruptive.\n\n
        The reign of Mehmed I as sultan of the re united empire lasted only eight years before his
        death, but he had also been the most powerful brother contending for the throne and de facto
        ruler of most of the empire for nearly the whole preceding period of 11 years of the Ottoman
        Civil War that passed between his father s captivity at Ankara.\n\n
</string>
    <string name="life_intro_muratii">
        Murad II s reign was marked by the long war he fought against the Christian feudal lords of the
        Balkans and the Turkish beyliks in Anatolia, a conflict that lasted 25 years.\n\n
        Murad II then formed a new army called Azap in 1421 and marched through the Byzantine Empire and
        laid siege to Constantinople. While Murad was besieging the city, the Byzantines, in league with
        some independent Turkish Anatolian states, sent the sultan younger brother Küçük Mustafa (who
        was only 13 years old) to rebel against the sultan and besiege Bursa.\n\n Murad had to abandon the
        siege of Constantinople in order to deal with his rebellious brother. He caught Prince Mustafa
        and executed him. The Anatolian states that had been constantly plotting against him.\n\n
        Murad II then declared war against Venice, the Karamanid Emirate, Serbia and Hungary. The
        Karamanids were defeated in 1428 and Venice withdrew in 1432 following the defeat at the second
        Siege of Thessalonica in 1430.\n\n
        In 1448 he defeated the Christian coalition at the Second Battle of Kosovo (the first one took
        place in 1389). When the Balkan front was secured, Murad II turned east to defeat Timur s son.
        In 1450 Murad II led his army into Albania and unsuccessfully besieged the Castle of Kruje in an
        effort to defeat the resistance led by Skanderbeg.\n\n
        In the winter of 1450–1451, Murad II fell ill, and died in Edirne. He was succeeded by his son
        Mehmed II (1451–81).\n\n
        Murad II successfully painted himself as a simple soldier who did not partake in royal excesses,
        and as a noble ghazi sultan who sought to consolidate Muslim power against non Muslims such as
        the Venetians and Hungarians.\n\n Through this self presentation, he got the support of the Muslim
        population of not only the Ottoman territories, for both himself and his extensive, expensive
        campaigns, but also the greater Muslim populations in the Dar al Islam – such as the Mamluks and
        the Muslim Delhi Sultanates of India.\n\n Murad II was basically presenting himself not only as “a
        ghazi king who fights caffres [nonmuslims], but also serves as protector and master of lesser
        ghazis.”\n\n
</string>

    <string name="life_intro_mehmetii">
        Mehmed II, also known as The Conqueror is one of the famous sultans of Ottoman Empire with his
        intelligence. Mehmed II ruled the Ottoman for a brief time, from 1444 to 1446, after his father.
        After that time Sultan Murad II renounced the throne but when he died Mehmed II ruled the
        Ottoman Empire from 1451 to 1481.\n\n Mehmet II was a genius statesman and a military leader who was
        also interested in literature, fine arts and monumental architecture. He was educated by famous
        scholar Aksemseddin and according to Ottoman historians he was speaking seven languages
        fluently.\n\n

        Mehmed II was born as a son of Sultan Murad I and Huma Hatun on the night of 29th binded to 30th
        March 1432, in Edirne. His early childhood passed on Edirne for a while.\n\n He motivated for taking
        the city of Constantinople, The City of World\'s Desire, by Prophet Hz Muhammed’s words for the conqueror of Constantinople
        decades ago; “One day, Constantinople will be conquered. How wonderful and blessed are the
        commander of its conquest and his soldiers!” Sultan Mehmed II, overthrew the Byzantine Empire by
        conquering Constantinople as consolidating the Ottoman Empire and marking the end of the Middle
        Ages. He took the name "conqueror" (fatih) after the conquest of Istanbul on 29th May 1453.\n\n The
        conquest of Istanbul spelled the end of the Byzantine Empire and entered a phase of urban
        revival under the wise and tolerant administrations of Mehmed and his immediate successors.\n\n

        The capture of Istanbul was followed by a long succession of campaigns which resulted in a
        tremendous extension of direct Ottoman rule. After the conquest of the city, Mehmed the
        Conqueror marched towards Morea and captured the cities of Greece one after another.\n\n However, he
        was threatened from the rear by the principality of Karaman and therefore turned to Anatolia to
        vanquish them and to annex their territory. He then conquered the area close to western Black
        Sea and appointed as governor Kızıl Ahmet who was the founder of the principality Isfen diyar.
        Afterwards, he fought Uzun Hasan, the ruler of the Akkoyunlus and overcame him.\n\n Among those areas
        that fell to Mehmet II were Serbia, Greece, the Empire of Trezibizond, Wallachia, Bosnia,
        Karaman, Albania and several Venetian and Geneose maritime establishments.\n\n

        Mehmed 2nd’s wifes were Gulbahar Hatun, Gulshah Hatun, Sitti Mukrime Hatun, Cicek Hatun, Helene
        Hatun, Anna Hatun and Alexias Hatun. He had a daughter named Gevrehan Sultana and sons; Mustafa,
        Bayezid II (Sultan after Mehmed II), Cem and Korkut.\n\n Mehmed II was dressed in the simple and
        heroic manner of his great grandfather Çelebi Mehmed. His turban consisted of a   mücevveze   (a
        tall cylindrical headgear) in military style, wound round with coiled gauze. This special type
        of turban became fashionable among later sultans.\n\n

        The Codes of Mehmed II was very important document for his era. It was a constitution ordering
        the state men duties and legalizing the fratricide for the order of the empire.\n\n This code
        included establishing various organizational positions, produce a form of law that suited the
        growing empire s geography and state organizations after the conquest of Constantinople.
\n\n
        He ruled the Ottoman Empire for 30 years and joined 25 campaigns himself. He was a very strict
        statesman and a very brave soldier. The great emperor had died on 3rd May 1481 and he was buried
        in "Fatih Turbesi" (tomb), near the Mosque of Fatih in Istanbul.\n\n After the Sultan’s death, the
        Ottoman Empire remained culturally and geographically strong.
</string>

    <string name="life_intro_suleman">
        Sultan of the Ottoman Empire from 1520 until his death in 1566. Under his administration, the
        Ottoman state ruled over at least 25 million people.
        Süleyman was the only son of Sultan Selim I.\n\n He became sancak beyi (governor) of Kaffa in Crimea
        during the reign of his grandfather Bayezid II and of Manisa in western Asia Minor in the reign
        of Selim I.\n\n
        Süleyman succeeded his father as sultan in September 1520 and began his reign with campaigns
        against the Christian powers in central Europe and the Mediterranean. Belgrade fell to him in
        1521 and Rhodes, long under the rule of the Knights of St. John, in 1522–23. At Mohács, in
        August 1526, Süleyman broke the military strength of Hungary, the Hungarian king, Louis II,
        losing his life in the battle.\n\n
        Süleyman waged three major campaigns against Persia. The first (1534–35) gave the Ottomans
        control over the region of Erzurum in eastern Asia Minor and also witnessed the Ottoman conquest
        of Iraq, a success that rounded off the achievements of Selim I.\n\n The second campaign (1548–49)
        brought much of the area around Lake Van under Ottoman rule.  But the third (1554–55) served
        rather as a warning to the Ottomans of the difficulty of subduing the Ṣafavid state in Persia.
        The first formal peace between the Ottomans and the Ṣafavids was signed in 1555, but it offered
        no clear solution to the problems confronting the Ottoman sultan on his eastern frontier.\n\n
        Süleyman surrounded himself with administrators and statesmen of unusual ability, men such as
        his grand viziers (chief ministers) İbrahim, Rüstem, and Mehmed Sokollu. ʿUlamāʾ (specialists in
        Islamic law), notably Abū al Suʿūd (Hoca Çelebi) and Kemalpaşazade, made the period memorable,
        as did the great Turkish poet Bâkî and the architect Sinan.\n\n Süleyman built strong fortresses to
        defend the places he took from the Christians and adorned the cities of the Islamic world
        (including Mecca, Damascus, and Baghdad) with mosques, bridges, aqueducts, and other public
    works. In general, Süleyman completed the task of transforming the previously Byzantine city of
            Constantinople into Istanbul, a worthy centre for a great Turkish and Islamic empire.\n\n
</string>

    <string name="life_intro_muradiv">
        He was only 11 when he ascended the throne. His reign is most notable for the Ottoman–Safavid
        War (1623–39), of which the outcome would permanently part the Caucasus between the two Imperial
        powers for around two centuries, while it also roughly laid the foundation for the current
        Turkey–Iran–Iraq borders.\n\n
        Murad IV was for a long time under the control of his relatives and during his early years as
        Sultan, his mother, Kösem Sultan, essentially ruled through him. The Empire fell into anarchy;
        the Safavid Empire invaded Iraq almost immediately, Northern Anatolia erupted in revolts, and in
        1631 the Janissaries stormed the palace and killed the Grand Vizier, among others. Murad IV
        feared suffering the fate of his elder brother, Osman II (1618–22), and decided to assert his
        power.\n\n
        A man of courage, determination, and violent temperament, Murad did not follow closely the
        precepts of the Sharīʿah (Islamic law) and was the first Ottoman sultan to execute a shaykh
        al islām (the highest Muslim dignitary in the empire).\n\n He was able to restore order, however,
        and to straighten out state finances. Murad IV tried to quell the corruption that had grown
        during the reigns of previous Sultans, and that had not been checked while his mother was ruling
        through proxy. Murad IV banned alcohol, tobacco, and coffee in Istanbul. Though, it is said that
        he died of heavy drinking! Wallah Alim.\n\n
        Murad IV was able to retake Iraq (1638), Iran remained a major threat. Finally, a long war with
        Venice (1645–69), occasioned by Ottoman efforts to capture Crete, exposed Istanbul to a major
        Venetian naval attack.\n\n Although the Venetians finally were pushed back in a naval campaign
        culminating in the Ottoman conquest of Crete (1669), they still posed a major threat that, like
        those which had occurred earlier in the century, stimulated the ruling class to accept needed
        reforms.\n\n The reforms introduced during the 17th century were too limited in nature and scope,
        however, to permanently arrest the Ottoman decline.\n\n
        The reforms essentially were no more than efforts to restore the inherited system of government
        and society that had operated successfully in the past.\n\n Efforts were made to restore the timar
        and tax farm systems as the basis of the administration and army and to limit taxes to the
        limits imposed by law. Provincial revolts were suppressed, peasants were forced back to the
        land, and cultivation was increased.\n\n
        Such reforms were sufficient to end the immediate difficulties. But they were successful only
        temporarily because the reformers were allowed to act against only the results of the decay and
        not its cause.\n\n

</string>

    <string name="life_intro_abdulhamitii">
        Modernization of the Ottoman Empire occurred during his reign, including reform of the
        bureaucracy, the extension of the Rumelia Railway and Anatolia Railway and the construction of
        the Baghdad Railway and Hejaz Railway.\n\n In addition, a system for population registration and
        control over the press was established along with the first local modern law school in 1898.\n\n
        The most far reaching of these reforms were in education: many professional schools were
        established, including Law School, School of Arts, School of Trades, Civil Engineering School,
        The Veterinarian School, The Customs School, The Farming School, The Linguistic School, and
        more.\n\n The University of Istanbul, although shut down by Hamid II in 1881, was reopened in 1900,
        and a network of secondary, primary, and military schools was extended throughout the empire.
        Railway and telegraph systems were developed by primarily German firms.\n\n
        Shehzade Abdul Hamid II was born at the Topkapı Palace in Istanbul (Constantinople), the capital
        of the Ottoman Empire, on September 21, 1842. He was the son of Sultan Abdulmejid Han.\n\n
        He was a skilled carpenter and personally crafted some high quality furniture, which can be seen
        today at the Yıldız Palace, Sale Kosku and Beylerbeyi Palace in Istanbul. Abdul Hamid II was
        also interested in opera and personally wrote the first ever Turkish translations of many opera
        classics.\n\n
        Russian Ottoman war of 1877–78 threatened the existence of the Ottoman Empire. Abdul Hamid used
        these difficult war filled times to recreate the absolutist regime and to dissolve the
        parliament and usurping all political power until his overthrow.\n\n
        Abdul Hamid worked with the Young Ottomans to realize some form of constitutional arrangement.
        The Young Ottomans believed that the modern parliamentary system was a restatement of the
        practice of consultation, or shura, which had existed in early Islam.\n\n
        Russia continued to mobilize for war. However, everything changed when the British fleet
        approached the capital from the Sea of Marmara. Early in 1877 the Ottoman Empire went to war
        with the Russian Empire.\n\n
        Abdul Hamid s biggest fear, near dissolution, was realized with the Russian declaration of war
        on 24 April 1877. In that conflict, the Ottoman Empire fought without help from European allies.
        Russian chancellor Prince Gorchakov had effectively purchased Austrian neutrality with the
        Reichstadt Agreement.\n\n The British Empire, though still fearing the Russian threat to British
        dominance in Southern Asia, did not involve itself in the conflict because of public opinion
        against the Ottomans.\n\n
        Cyprus, Egypt, and Sudan remained as Ottoman provinces "on paper" until 1914 when Britain
        officially annexed those territories in response to the Ottoman participation in World War I on
        the side of the Central Powers.\n\n
        In early 1897 a Greek expedition, sailed to Crete to overthrow Ottoman rule on the island. This
        act was followed by war, in which the Ottoman Empire defeated Greece.\n\n
        In 1912, when Salonica fell to Greece, he was returned to captivity in Constantinople. He spent
        his last days studying, carpentering and writing his memoirs in custody at Beylerbeyi Palace in
        the Bosphorus, in the company of his wives and children, where he died on 10 February 1918.\n\n Just
        a few months before his brother, Mehmed V, the Sultan. He was buried in Constantinople.

        In 1930, his nine widows and thirteen children were granted $50 million from his estate,
        following a lawsuit that lasted five years. His estate was worth $1.5 billion.\n\n
        Abdul Hamid was the last Sultan of the Ottoman Empire to hold absolute power.
        Abdul Hamid wrote poetry, following on the footsteps of many other Ottoman sultans. One of his
        poems translates thus:\n\n

        My Lord I know you are the Dear One (Al Aziz)\n
        … And no one but you are the Dear One\n
        You are the One, and nothing else\n
        My God take my hand in these hard times\n
        My God be my helper in this critical hour\n

        He was extremely fond of Sherlock Holmes novels.\n
</string>

    <string name="war_r_o">
        A series of wars fought between the Russian Empire and the Ottoman Empire between the 17th and
        20th centuries. It was one of the longest series of military conflicts in European history.\n\n
        Russian army organized the Crimean campaigns of 1687 and 1689. After the Russians had defeated
        the pro Swedish Empire Ukrainian Cossacks led by Ivan Mazepa and Swedes in the Battle of Poltava
        in 1709, Charles XII of Sweden managed to persuade the Ottoman Sultan Ahmed III to declare war
        on Russia on November 20, 1710.\n\n
        By the late 17th century, the Iranian Safavid dynasty, which neighbored both empires and had
        been one of the greatest rivals for Turkey for centuries (16th–19th centuries), had been heavily
        declining.\n\n Taking advantage of the situation, Russia and the Ottoman Empire conquered swaths of
        its territory. Comprising contemporary Dagestan, Azerbaijan, and Northern Iran, which was
        taken by Peter I in the Russo Persian War (1722–1723); the Ottomans took the territory to the
        west, comprising modern day Armenia, parts of Eastern Anatolia, as well as western Iran.\n\n The
        gains by both were confirmed in the Treaty of Constantinople (1724). For a few years, they
        bordered each other along a large territory in the Caucasus, which caused further frictions.\n\n
        Russia managed to secure a favourable international situation by signing treaties with Persia in
        1732 and 1735.
        Russia entered into another war with the Ottoman Empire in 1736, prompted by raids on Ukraine by
        Crimean Tatars and the military campaign of the Crimean khan in the Caucasus.\n\n In May 1736, the
        Russian army launched an invasion of the Crimean peninsula.
        ustria entered the war against Turkey in July 1737 but was defeated a number of times.\n\n In
        August, Russia, Austria and Turkey began negotiations in Nemirov, which would turn out to be
        fruitless.
        In 1787 the Ottomans demanded that Russia vacate the Crimea. Russia declared war, but Ottoman
        preparations were inadequate and the moment was ill chosen, now that Russia and Austria were in
        alliance, a fact Turkey became aware of only after events were already in motion. The Turks
        drove back the Austrians from Mehadia and overran the Banat (1789); but in Moldavia
        Field Marshal Pyotr Rumyantsev was successful and captured Iaşi and Khotin.\n\n
        Fall of Ottomans\n\n
        by the 1820s the Ottoman armies were unable to put down the Greek War of Independence in
        southern Greece. The great powers of Europe decided to intervene and assist Greece with its
        independence. Thus Greece became the first independent country created out of a section of the
        Ottoman Empire.\n\n
        When in 1853 Russia destroyed the entire Ottoman fleet at Sinop, Britain and France concluded
        that armed intervention on the side of the Ottomans was the only way to halt a massive Russian
        expansion.\n\n
</string>

    <string name="war_jer">
        When the United Kingdom captured Jerusalem from the Ottomans, the battle was significant for
        mostly symbolic reasons. In fact, the battle itself was unremarkable from a strategic point of
        view.\n\n
        The Ottoman Empire had been on the ropes for quite some time, and the Allies could use fresh
        resources against Istanbul thanks to America’s entrance into the war at the beginning of 1917.
        If America have not involved into WWI, the results could be a lot different!\n\n
        What was less predictable than the fall of Jerusalem to the Allies was how the local political
        scene would play out in the absence of shrewd Ottoman governance.
        Ottoman entered into allience with Austarian Hungarian Empire and Germany.
</string>

    <string name="war_gura">
        Little is known about the Ottoman presence in East Africa and the Indian Ocean, but this is
        changing, slowly but surely.
        There is also less of a focus on the Ottoman use of proxies to fight their wars.\n\n Much of the
        sociological focus of Ottoman warfare is on conscripts, but the Ottomans used proxies well,
        perhaps not as well as the British, Dutch, and French, but well enough that in the late 1870s
        Egyptian troops invaded Ethiopia for Ottoman purposes.\n\n
        The invasion forced the Ethiopians to cease hostilities against Ottoman vassals strewn along the
        Red Sea (present day Eritrea).
</string>

    <string name="war_alg">
        In 1830, France was yet again a monarchy and the Ottomans in Algeria were demanding war
        reparations from Napoleon’s campaign. The new king of France, Charles X, found this offensive
        and, instead of making a payment, launched an invasion.\n\n
        Algiers became a part of France, but on July 4 a revolution in France occurred and Charles X was
        overthrown. The conquest of Algiers led to a revolution in France.
        It caused a loss in Ottoman Territory.\n\n
</string>

    <string name="war_acre">
        The Ottomans won a crucial victory against Napoleon army in Asia, after allying themselves with
        the United Kingdom.
        The Siege of Acre was Napoleon first defeat in almost three years, and marked a turning point in
        the global allies war against France.\n\n
        The Siege of Acre of 1799 was an unsuccessful French siege of the Ottoman defended, walled city
        of Acre (now Akko in modern Israel) and was the turning point of Napoleon invasion of Egypt and
        Syria.\n\n It was Napoleon`s first strategic defeat as three years previously he had been tactically
        defeated at the Second Battle of Bassano.
        The French attempted to lay siege on 20 March using only their infantry. Napoleon believed the
        city would capitulate quickly to him.\n\n
        A Royal Navy helped to reinforce the Ottoman defences and supplied the city with additional
        cannon manned by sailors and marines. Smith used his command of the sea to capture the French
        siege artillery being sent by a flotilla of gunboats from Egypt and to bombard the coastal road
        from Jaffa.\n\n
        Defenders anchored the line of battle ships Tigre and Theseus so their broadsides could assist
        the defence. The gunboats, which were of shallower draft, could come in closer, and together
        they helped repel repeated French assaults.\n\n
        However, after suffering many casualties to open this entry point, Napoleon soldiers found, on
        trying to penetrate the city, that Farhi and DePhelipoux had, in the meantime, built a second
        wall, several feet deeper within the city where al Jazzar s garden was.\n\n Discovery of this
        new construction convinced Napoleon and his men that the probability of their taking the city
        was minimal. Moreover, after the assault was again repelled, Turkish reinforcements from Rhodes
        were able to land.\n\n
        Having underestimated the stubborn attitude of the defending forces combined with a British
        blockade of French supply harbours and harsh weather conditions, Napoleon s forces were left
        hungry, cold and damp. Plague had struck the French camp as a result of the desperate condition
        of the men, and had by now led to the deaths of about 2,000 soldiers.\n\n
        In 1805, Napoleon asserted that if he had: been able to take Acre [in 1799], I would have put
        on a turban, I would have made my soldiers wear big Turkish trousers, and I would have exposed
        them to battle only in case of extreme necessity.\n\n I would have made them into a Sacred
        Battalion, my Immortals. I would have finished the war against the Turks with Arabic, Greek, and
        Armenian troops. Instead of a battle in Moravia, I would have won a Battle of Issus, I would
        have made myself emperor of the East, and I would have returned to Paris by way of
        Constantinople.\n\n
        </string>

    <string name="war_vienna">
        In the late 17th century, the Ottomans had managed to push from Constantinople to the gates of
        Vienna, deep within the heart of Christendom. The situation was so dire from the point of view
        of the Europeans that the Holy Roman Empire and the Polish Lithuanian Commonwealth   bitter
        enemies   joined forces to turn back the Muslims from the East.\n\n The united front of Catholic
        and Protestant allies managed to turn back the massive Ottoman siege, so totally, in fact, that
        the Holy Roman Empire chased the Ottomans out of Hungary and some of the Balkans, too. A lot to
        learn
        from the history!\n\n
        </string>

    <string name="war_chal">
        While the Ottomans had enjoyed mostly success in their westward expansion into Christendom, the
        East remained a tougher task. This began to change after the Battle of Chaldiran, fought between
        the Ottomans and the Persians (governed at that time by the Safavid dynasty).\n\n
        The battle led to Ottoman territorial expansion into the East, with the whole of Anatolia being
        annexed along with what are now Kurdish lands. The Battle of Chaldiran also ended Shi’a
        resistance to Ottoman (a Sunni empire) rule. Because, the Shi’ites could no longer appeal to an
        outside power for help.\n\n
        While the Safavids, and Persia, were shaken by the defeat, the dynasty survived and the two
        rivals continued their beef for another 300 years. In many ways, the factions involved in the
        Battle of Chaldiran are still at work today.\n\n
        </string>

    <string name="war_zonc">
        Fought between the Ottomans and the merchant princes of Venice, the Battle of Zonchio marked the
        first time in history that cannons were employed on ships.\n\n
        Once Constantinople fell, the Ottomans came into almost immediate conflict with a number of
        Christian states in Europe, and one of Europe’s major powers at the time, Venice.
        Officially, seven wars were fought between the two polities, with the Ottomans winning the bulk
        of them. The Ottoman wars against Venice led to the latter’s decline as a regional power, and
        led to more and more territorial acquisition in Christian lands.\n\n
        Istanbul was marching westward, but it was also sailing westward, and Ottoman naval power after
        the Battle of Zonchio was not to be trifled with.\n\n
        The Ottomans and Venetians soon confronted each other for a second time at the Second Battle of
        Lepanto, which is also known as the Battle of Modon, and the Ottomans were victorious under
        Kemal Reis.\n\n

        </string>

    <string name="war_ankara">
        This battle, between two Super Poweres of the World, and sadly, both were Muslims!!!
        This battle, which the Ottomans lost, ceded to Timur and his realm leadership of the Muslim
        world.\n\n It also plunged the empire into chaos, and led directly to the Ottoman Interregnum, a
        devastating 11 year civil war. The battle itself included war elephants, Christian vassals
        from the Balkans, and was the only time in the 500 year history of the empire that a Sultan was
        captured in battle (he died after three months in captivity).\n\n The Ottoman Empire, far from being
        the major player it eventually became, got a taste of what it was like to fight major battles
        against major foes.
        </string>

    <string name="war_constant">

        The siege of Constantinople introduced to the world the Ottoman Empire as a major player on the
        world stage. The Ottomans had slowly been expanding their empire westward, and the conquest of
        Constantinople, the capital city of the Byzantine Empire heir to Rome itself marked their
        arrival in Europe and Christendom.\n\n The Ottomans renamed the city Istanbul and promptly made
        the city the capital of the Ottoman Empire. The Fall of Constantinople, and thus a major port
        city and trading route to Asia, to the Ottomans forced many Europeans to look for other ways to
        reach the spice markets of the East.\n\n

        Altough his early age, Sultan II Mehmed, started to prepare siege for İstanbul. He wanted to be
        the commander as Prophet Hz Muhammed mentioned the conqueror of Constantinople; “One day,
        Constantinople will be conquered.\n\n How wonderful and blessed are the commander of its conquest
        and his soldiers!” decades ago. First he took precautions with strategic tactics in both inside
        and outside of the state. After this, he moved to conquer Constantinople.
\n\n
        Constantinople had been an imperial for many years. The city were bombarded by cannon fires
        which was designed by Mehmed the Second himself. Constantinople had been attacked in the past
        many times, but its great walls always prevailed.\n\n Sultan Mehmed, II changed this with the use of
        cannons forever. Sultan s massive cannon fired on the walls for weeks.
\n\n
        Baltaoglu Suleyman Bey launched the first attack to enter the Golden Horn gulf on 9th April 1453
        and failed to break the chains which was placed at the mouth of the horn.\n\n This chain, which
        floated on wooden logs, was strong enough to prevent any Ottoman ship from entering Golden Horn.
        The victory of the Pope’s Christian and Genoese ships decreased the morale of the Ottoman
        army.\n\n

        In short, In the morning of 22th April, Eastern Roman Empire woke up with a surprise and
        terrified when they saw Ottoman galleys in the horn.
\n\n
        On 29th May, the Ottoman army attacked for the final assault. The siege lasted from Friday, 6
        April 1453 until 29 May 1453 Tuesday when the city was conquered by the Ottomans under the
        command of Sultan II. Mehmed. A new era started on the world and a new balance came through by
        the conquest of Constantinople.
\n\n
        </string>

    <string name="war_mongols">

        The Battle of Ain Jalut: When Möngke Khan became Great Khan in 1251, he immediately set out to
        implement his grandfather Genghis Khan\ s plan for world empire. To lead the task of subduing
        the nations of the West, he selected his brother, another of Genghis Khan\ s grandsons, Hulagu
        Khan.\n\n
        In 1260, Hulagu sent envoys to Qutuz in Cairo, demanding his surrender:
        “ From the King of Kings of the East and West, the Great Khan. To Qutuz the Mamluk, who fled to
        escape our swords.\n\n You should think of what happened to other countries and submit to us. You
        have heard how we have conquered a vast empire and have purified the earth of the disorders that
        tainted it. We have conquered vast areas, massacring all the people. You cannot escape from the
        terror of our armies.\n\n Where can you flee? What road will you use to escape us? Our horses are
        swift, our arrows sharp, our swords like thunderbolts, our hearts as hard as the mountains, our
        soldiers as numerous as the sand. Fortresses will not detain us, nor armies stop us. Your
        prayers to God will not avail against us.\n\n We are not moved by tears nor touched by lamentations.
        Only those who beg our protection will be safe. Hasten your reply before the fire of war is
        kindled. Resist and you will suffer the most terrible catastrophes.\n\n We will shatter your mosques
        and reveal the weakness of your God and then will kill your children and your old men together.
        At present you are the only enemy against whom we have to march. ”\n\n

        Shortly before the battle, Hulagu withdrew from the Levant with the bulk of his army, leaving
        his forces west of the Euphrates with only one tumen (nominally 10,000 men but usually
        smaller).\n\n The Mamluk Sultan Qutuz at that time allied with a fellow Mamluk, Baibars, Turks
        under Ertugrul Gazi, who chose to ally himself with Qutuz in the face of a greater enemy, after
        the Mongols captured Damascus and most of Bilad al Sham.\n\n
        When news arrived that the Mongols had crossed the Jordan River, Sultan Qutuz and his forces
        proceeded southeast toward the spring at Ain Jalut in the Jezreel Valley. The first to
        advance were the Mongols, whose force also included troops from the Kingdom of Georgia and about
        500 troops from the Armenian Kingdom of Cilicia, both of which had submitted to Mongol
        authority.\n\n
        The two armies fought for many hours, with Baibars most of the time implementing hit and run
        tactics, in order to provoke the Mongol troops and at the same time preserve the bulk of his
        troops intact.\n\n
        Some distance away, Qutuz watched with his private legion. When Qutuz saw the left wing of the
        Mamluk army almost destroyed by the desperate Mongols seeking an escape route, Qutuz threw away
        his combat helmet, so that his warriors could recognize him.\n\n He was seen the next moment
        rushing fiercely towards the battlefield yelling "wa islamah!" ("Oh my Islam"), urging his army
        to keep firm, and advanced towards the weakened side, followed by his own unit.
\n\n
        The Mongols were pushed back and fled to a vicinity of Bisan, followed by Qutuz forces, but they
        managed to reorganize and return to the battlefield, making a successful counterattack.
        Kitbuqa and almost the whole Mongol army that had remained in the region perished. Baibars
        became the new Sultan.\n\n Local Ayyubid emirs sworn to the Mamluk sultanate subsequently
        defeated another Mongol force of 6,000 at Homs, which ended the first Mongol expedition into
        Syria.  Baibars and his successors would go on to capture the last of the Crusader states in
        The Holy Land by 1291.\n\n

        </string>

    <string name="war_s_mongols">

        Suljuks were predecessors of Ottomans. The Seljuk Empire in Persia was at its peak during the
        reign of Alp Arsalan and his son Malik Shah. With the death of Malik Shah, began the decline of
        this great empire.\n\n The borders of the Seljuk Sultanate were under constant pressure from the
        Crusaders in the west, the Arabs in the south and the Mongols in the east.
        The Battle of Köse Dağ was fought between the Sultanate of Rum ruled by the Seljuq dynasty and
        the Mongol Empire on June 26, 1243 at the defile of Köse Dağ, a location between Erzincan and
        Gümüşhane in modern northeastern Turkey.\n\n
        he decisive battle was fought at Köse Dağ on June 26, 1243. The primary sources do not record
        the size of the opposing armies but suggest that the Mongols faced a numerically superior
        force.\n\n
        The defeat resulted in a period of turmoil in Anatolia and led directly to the decline and
        disintegration of the Seljuq state. The Empire of Trebizond became a vassal state of the Mongol
        empire.\n\n Furthermore, the Armenian Kingdom of Cilicia became a vassal state of the Mongols. Real
        power over Anatolia was exercised by the Mongols.
        </string>

    <string name="forth_crusade">
        The Fourth Crusade (1202 to 1204) was a Latin Christian armed expedition called by Pope Innocent
        III. The majority of the crusading army that set out from Venice in early October 1202
        originated from areas within France.\n\n Early in October 1202, a fleet of 200 ships set sail
        from the lagoon of Venice. The goal of this expedition, this Fourth Crusade, was to win back the
        holy city of Jerusalem. Conquered by Islamic armies in the 7th century. Jerusalem fell to the
        Muslim Saladin, the Greatest Sultan of his time, An Nasir Salah ad Din Yusuf ibn Ayyub known as
        Sultan Salah ad Din Ayoubi in the Muslim World, who then stalemated a recovery attempt by the
        Third Crusade (1189 to 92).\n\n The Fourth Crusade was to follow a new strategy: strike at Egypt,
        the base of Muslim power. But it never reached its goal. Instead, a bizarre twist of fate turned
        the latest crusaders in a totally unexpected direction! \n \n They, instead of targeting Islamic
        cities they attacked another Chirstian city, one of the greatest cities of all times,
        Constantinople, capital of the Byzantine Empire.\n\n After this attack, The Byzantine Empire
        never recovered and was finally and forever extinguished by the Turks in 1453. \n \n Almost none
        of the crusaders ever made it to the Holy Land, and the unstable Latin Empire siphoned off much
        of the crusading energy of Europe.\n\n The legacy of the Fourth Crusade was the deep sense of
        betrayal the Latins had instilled in their Greek coreligionists.\n \n Turks, after this crusade
        became much more powerful, actually we can say that their way into Europe was paved by 4th
        crusade.\n\n
        </string>


    <string name="empire">
        Golden Period
        During the 16th and 17th centuries, at the height of its power under the reign of Suleiman the
        Magnificent, the Ottoman Empire was a multinational, multilingual empire controlling most of
        Southeast Europe, parts of Central Europe, Western Asia, parts of Eastern Europe and the
        Caucasus, North Africa and the Horn of Africa.\n\n At the beginning of the 17th century, the
        empire contained 32 provinces and numerous vassal states. Some of these were later absorbed into
        the Ottoman Empire, while others were granted various types of autonomy during the course of
        centuries.\n\n

        The Golden Age of Suleiman
\n\n
        The Ottoman Empire reached the peak of its power during the rule of Selim son, Suleiman the
        Magnificent (ruled 1520  66) and his grandson Selim II (1566   74).
\n\n
        Suleiman came to the throne as one of the wealthiest rulers in the world. His strength owed much
        to the work his father Selim had done in stabilising government, removing opposition,
        frightening (but not succesfully conquering) the Safavid Empire of Iran into adopting a
        non aggression policy, and conquering the Mamluk empire of Egypt and Syria.
\n\n

        The Turkish word for "Ottoman" (Osmanlı) originally referred to the tribal followers of Osman in
        the fourteenth century, and subsequently came to be used to refer to the empire s
        military administrative elite.
    \n\n
        In Western Europe, the two names "Ottoman Empire" and "Turkey" were often used interchangeably,
        with "Turkey" being increasingly favoured both in formal and informal situations.
        In the century after the death of Osman I, Ottoman rule began to extend over Anatolia and the
        Balkans. Osman s son, Orhan, captured the northwestern Anatolian city of Bursa in 1326.
        \n\n
        Making it the new capital of the Ottoman state and supplanting Byzantine control in the region.
        The important port city of Thessaloniki was captured from the Venetians in 1387 and sacked. The
        Ottoman victory at Kosovo in 1389 effectively marked the end of Serbian power in the region,
        paving the way for Ottoman expansion into Europe.
        \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="mw_countries">
        History of Ottoman ruled countries
    \n\n
        Albania\n
        Algeria\n
        Armenia\n
        Bosnia and Herzegovina\n
        Bulgaria\n
        Cyprus\n
        Egypt\n
        Eritrea\n
        Greece\n
        Hungary\n
        Iraq\n
        Jordan\n
        Kosovo\n
        Libya\n
        Macedonia\n
        Montenegro\n
        Palestine\n
        Serbia\n
        Syria\n
        Tunisia\n
        Turkey\n
        Ukraine
        \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="success">
        There were many reasons why the Ottoman Empire was so successful:
\n\n
\n\n         Highly centralised
    \n\n     Power was always transferred to a single person, and not split between rival princes
        \n\n The Ottoman Empire was successfully ruled by a single family for 7 centuries.
        \n\n State run education system
\n\n         Religion was incorporated in the state structure, and the Sultan was regarded as "the protector
        of Islam".
    \n\n     State run judicial system
        \n\n Ruthless in dealing with local leaders
\n\n         Promotion to positions of power largely depended on merit
    \n\n     Created alliances across political and racial groups
        \n\n United by Islamic ideology
\n\n         United by Islamic warrior code with ideal of increasing Muslim territory through Jihad
    \n\n     United by Islamic organisational and administrative structures
        \n\n Highly pragmatic, taking the best ideas from other cultures and making them their own
\n\n         Encouraged loyalty from other faith groups
    \n\n     Private power and wealth were controlled
        \n\n Very strong military
\n\n         Strong slave based army
    \n\n     Expert in developing gunpowder as a military tool
        \n\n Military ethos pervaded whole administration
\n\n
        At first the rule of the Ottoman Sultans was insecure. To consolidate their Empire the Ottoman
        Sultans formed groups of fanatical fighters   the orders of the Janissaries, a crack infantry
        group of slaves and Christian converts to Islam.
\n\n
        The Ottomans inflicted a series of defeats on the declining Christian Byzantine Empire and then
        quickly expanded westward.
    \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="economy">
        Istanbul became not only a political and military capital, but because of its position at the
        junction of Europe, Africa, and Asia, one of the great trade centres of the world. Another
        important city was Bursa, which was a centre of the silk trade.
\n\n
        Some of the later Ottoman conquests were clearly intended to give them control of other trade
        routes.
\n\n
        Among the goods traded were:
\n\n
    \n\n     Silk and other cloth
        \n\n Musk
\n\n         Rhubarb
    \n\n     Porcelain from China
        \n\n Spices such as pepper
\n\n         Dyestuffs such as indigo
    \n\n     The economic strength of the Empire also owed much to Mehmet s policy of increasing the number
        of traders and artisans in the Empire.

        \n\n
        He first encouraged merchants to move to Istanbul, and later forcibly resettled merchants from
        captured territories such as Caffa.
\n\n
        He also encouraged Jewish traders from Europe to migrate to Istanbul and set up in business
        there. Later rulers continued these policies.

\n\n
        </string>

    <string name="decline">
        The power of the empire was waning by 1683 when the second and last attempt was made to conquer
        Vienna. It failed. Without the conquest of Europe and the acquisition of significant new wealth
        the Empire lost momentum and went into a slow decline.
\n\n
        Several other factors contributed to the Empire s decline:
\n\n
\n\n         The European powers wanted to expand
    \n\n     Economic problems
        \n\n Competition from trade from the Americas
\n\n         Competition from cheap products from India and the Far East
    \n\n     Development of other trade routes
        \n\n Rising unemployment within the Empire
\n\n         Ottoman Empire became less centralised, and central control weakened
    \n\n     Sultans being less severe in maintaining rigorous standards of integrity in the administration
        of the Empire
        \n\n Sultans becoming less sensitive to public opinion
\n\n         The low quality Sultans of the 17th and 18th centuries
    \n\n     The ending of the execution of Sultan s sons and brothers, imprisoning them instead
\n\n
        The empire officially ended on the 1st November 1922, when the Ottoman sultanate was abolished
        and Turkey was declared a republic. The Ottoman caliphate continued as an institution, with
        greatly reduced authority, until it too was abolished on the 3rd March 1924.
        \n\n
        Yet despite their close observation of European science and technology, and their attempts to
        organise their own learning along European lines, the Ottomans failed to discover that European
        science and technology is based on supporting and promoting a culture of research. The
        connection between research and technology was almost entirely missing in Ottoman technology
        transfer until the mid 1800s.\n\n
        </string>


    <string name="military">
        Ottoman Classical Army was the military structure established by Mehmed II, during his
        reorganization of the state and the military. This was the major reorganization following Orhan
        I s standing army paid by salary rather than booty or fiefs. This army was the force during the
        rise of the Ottoman Empire.
\n\n
        The Janissaries were elite infantry units that formed the Ottoman Sultan s household troops and
        bodyguards. Sultan Murad I created the force in 1383. They began as an elite corps of slaves
        recruited from young Christian boys, and became famed for internal cohesion cemented by strict
        discipline and order. By 1620 they were hereditary and corrupt and an impediment to reform.
\n\n
        For all practical purposes, Janissaries belonged to the Sultan, carrying the title kapıkulu
        (Subject of the gate) indicating their collective bond with the Sultan. Janissaries were taught
        to consider the corps as their home and family, and the Sultan as their de facto father.\n\n The
        janissary corps was significant in a number of ways. The janissaries wore uniforms, were paid in
        cash as regular soldiers, and marched to distinctive music, by the mehter.\n\n

        Small arms (rifles, carbines and handguns) The Ottoman Army s most modern rifle – as good as any
        used by the other Great Powers – was the 7.65 mm M1903 Mauser bolt action rifle. This
        German designed and manufactured weapon used a five round removable box magazine and had an
        effective range of up to 600 m.\n\n
        The Ottomans also wanted to learn the new science of military organisation and strategy. They
        established centres for military education and training and reorganised their armies into
        officers of different ranks and military, medical, educational and administrative departments.
        Ottoman military advisors were often of European origin, or European converts to Islam.
\n\n
        The new educational institutions were organised by separating students according to age,
        employing teachers for specific subjects, organising teaching according to subject syllabuses,
        conducting qualifying examinations for students and sending teachers abroad for further
        education and training in the new disciplines.
\n\n
        </string>

    <string name="tech">
        Science and learning flourished throughout the period of empire, but particularly in its early
        centuries. Ottomans had contributed to the development of hospitals and healthcare, and
        witnessed advances in medicine, mining and military technology.\n\n
        Ottomans invented currently used surgical instruments such as forceps, scalpels, and catheters.
        The capture of Constantinople by the Ottomans caused many scholars to flee to Italy and bring
        with them knowledge that helped spark the Renaissance.\n\n
        Two centuries ago the Ottoman rulers of Turkey adopted technology, management and methods of
        learning from Europe. That experience has lessons for today s developing countries, says
        Ekmeleddin Ihsanoglu.\n\n
        Science and learning flourished throughout the period of empire, but particularly in its early
        centuries. Ottomans had contributed to the development of hospitals and healthcare, and
        witnessed advances in medicine, mining and military technology.\n\n They also set up a leading
        observatory in Istanbul and had established more than 300 centres of learning known as medreses.
        Students from all over the world came to study and carry out research in arithmetic, astronomy,
        philosophy and faith (known as the religious sciences ).\n\n
        Another insight comes from the establishment of the Imperial Naval Engineering College in 1773,
        perhaps the first modern technical institution in the Ottoman empire.\n\n The four year curriculum
        included practical aspects of engineering such as arithmetic, astronomy, ballistics, geometry
        and hydraulics. Subjects such as physics, chemistry and other natural sciences were not in the
        curriculum, and neither was metallurgy, essential for a proper understanding of civil and
        mechanical engineering.\n\n
        </string>


    <string name="women" tools:ignore="TypographyEllipsis">
        They say that behind every great man is a great woman. Perhaps this is an analogy with elements
        of truth, as history has shown time and time again, strong female leaders who managed to
        overcome the difficulties and challenges of maintaining fair power, rule and control over their
        respective kingdoms and sultanates in what was (and still is) male dominated politics.
        \n\nHürrem Sultan. …
      \n\n  Valide Safiye Sultan. …
       \n\n Kösem Sultan. ...
       \n\n Hatice Turhan Sultan. ...
       \n\n Safiye Sultan – Golden Queen of the Ottoman Empire. Safiye Sultan was the chief consort of Murad
        III and queen mother of Mehmed III. She was one of the most powerful chief consorts and queen
        mothers in Ottoman history.
        </string>


    <string name="hurrem">
        Roxelana, called Hurrem Sultan, probably entered the harem around fifteen years of age. The
        precise year that she entered the harem is unknown, but scholars believe that she became
        Suleiman s concubine around the time he became sultan in 1520.\n\n
        Later, Hurrem became the first woman to remain in the Sultan s court for the duration of her
        life. In the Ottoman imperial family tradition, a sultan s consort was to remain in the harem
        only until her son came of age (around 16 or 17), after which he would be sent away from the
        capital to govern a faraway province, and his mother would follow him.\n\n This tradition was called
        Sanjak Beyliği. The consorts were never to return to Istanbul unless their sons succeeded to the
        throne.\n\n
        In defiance of this age old custom, Hurrem stayed behind in the harem with her hunchback son
        Cihangir, even after her three other sons went to govern the empire s remote provinces.\n\n
        Hurrem became Süleyman s partner not only in the Sultan s household, but also in state affairs.
        Thanks to her intelligence, she acted as Süleyman s chief adviser on matters of state, and seems
        to have had an influence upon foreign policy and international politics.\n\n She frequently
        accompanied him as a political adviser. Hurrem s influence on Süleyman was so significant that
        rumors circulated around the Ottoman court that the sultan had been bewitched.\n\n
        Hurrem s influence in state affairs not only made her one of the most influential women, but
        also a controversial figure in Ottoman history, especially in her rivalry with Mahidevran Sultan
        and her son şehzade Mustafa, Pargalı Ibrahim Pasha, and Kara Ahmed Pasha.\n\n
        Hurrem and Mahidevran had borne Süleyman six şehzades (Ottoman princes), four of whom survived
        past the 1550s: Mustafa, Selim, Bayezid, and Cihangir. Of these, Mahidevran s son Mustafa was
        the eldest and preceded Hurrem s children in the order of succession.\n\n Traditionally, when a new
        sultan rose to power, all of his brothers were killed in order to ensure the stability of the
        empire. This practice is called kardeş katliamı.\n\n
        Hurrem acted as Süleyman s advisor on matters of state, and seems to have had an influence upon
        foreign policy and on international politics. Two of her letters to King Sigismund II Augustus
        of Poland (reigned 1548–1572) have survived, and during her lifetime the Ottoman Empire
        generally had peaceful relations with the Polish state within a Polish–Ottoman alliance.\n\n
        Hürrem died on 15 April 1558 and was buried in a domed mausoleum (türbe) decorated in exquisite
        Iznik tiles depicting the garden of paradise, perhaps in homage to her smiling and joyful
        nature.\n\n
        Hurrem Haseki Sultan, or Roxelana, is well known both in modern Turkey and in the West, and is
        the subject of many artistic works. In 1561, three years after Hurrem s death, the French author
        Gabriel Bounin wrote a tragedy titled La Soltane.\n\n
        In the 2003 TV miniseries, Hürrem Sultan, she was played by Turkish actress and singer Gülben
        Ergen. In the 2011–2014 TV series Muhteşem Yüzyıl, Hurrem Sultan is portrayed by Turkish German
        actress Meryem Uzerli from season one to season three and at the series last season she is
        portrayed by Turkish actress Vahide Perçin.\n\n
        </string>

    <string name="safia">
        In 1563, at the age of 13, she was presented as a slave to the future Murad III by Hümaşah
        Sultan, daughter of Şehzade Mehmed, son of Suleiman the Magnificent and Hürrem Sultan.
        Given the name Safiye ("the pure one"), she became a concubine of Murad (then the eldest son of
        Sultan Selim II). On 26 May 1566, she gave birth to Murad s son, the future Mehmed III, the same
        year Suleiman the Magnificent died.\n\n
        Safiye had been Murad s only concubine prior to his accession, and he continued having a
        monogamous relationship with her for several years into his sultanate.
        In 1583, Nurbanu accused Safiye of using witches and sorcerers to render Murad impotent and
        prevent him from taking new concubines.\n\n This resulted in the imprisonment and torture of Safiye
        s servants.
        When Murad died in 1595, Safiye arranged for her son Mehmed to succeed as sultan, and she became
        the Valide Sultan one of the most powerful in Ottoman history.\n\n Until her son s death in 1603,
        Ottoman politics were determined by a party headed by herself and Gazanfer Ağa, chief of the
        white eunuchs and head of the enderun (the imperial inner palace).\n\n
        Leslie Peirce points out in her book that Safiye was still alive during the first months of her
        daughter in law s retirement in the Old Palace between Mustafa I s two reigns, which means that
        she was alive at least until 1619 and died during the reign of her great grandson Osman II.
        Safiye was buried in Murad III s tomb.\n\n
        </string>

    <string name="kosem" tools:ignore="TypographyEllipsis">
        Kösem lived in the Ottoman Empire as a courtier during the reign of six sultans: Ahmed I,
        Mustafa I, Osman II, Murad IV, Ibrahim, and Mehmed IV. After her death, she was known by the
        names "Valide i Muazzama" (magnificent mother).\n\n
        As a Haseki Sultan to Ahmed I Kösem was considered his favorite consort and gave birth to many
        of his children.\n\n
        Venetian ambassador Simon Contarini mentions Kösem in his report in 1612 and portrays her as:
        "[A woman] of beauty and shrewdness, and furthermore … of many talents, she sings
        excellently, whence she continues to be extremely well loved by the king ... Not that she is
        respected by all, but she is listened to in some matters and is the favorite of the king, who
        wants her beside him continually."
       \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="turhan">
    \n\n    She and her mother in law, Kösem Sultan, are the only two women in Ottoman history to be
        regarded as official regents and had supreme control over the Ottoman Empire. Turhan Hatice
        herself was the only one in Ottoman history to equally share the power of running the entire
        empire with Ottoman Sultan legally, although in fact she transferred her political power to the
        grand vizier. As a result, Turhan became one of the prominent figures during the era known as
        Sultanate of Women.
        \n\n
        She was captured as a child during a Crimean slave raid in Rus and sold into slavery in the
        Ottoman Empire. When she was about 12 years old, Turhan was sent to the Imperial Harem at the
        Topkapı Palace as a gift, from the Khan of Crimea, to the mother of Sultan Ibrahim, Kösem
        Sultan.
        \n\n
        It was probably Kösem Sultan who gave Hatice to the Sultan as a concubine. Turhan would bear
        Ibrahim a son, the future sultan Mehmed IV, on 2 January 1642.
\n\n
        Turhan Hatice, Valide Sultan and regent to her young son, Mehmed IV, died in 1683. She was
        buried in the tomb of the Yeni Mosque. She lies alongside her son and her descendents.

    \n\n
    </string>


</resources>
